I mean, just a year or two, three years
ago,
a
the idea of like building a whole
feature and then just throwing it out,
we'd be like, that was such a waste of
time and money and resources. Now we can
just start over, you know, and it's not
a big deal. The mindset used to be like,
what is the just good enough version of
this feature because we're bootstrappers
and we want to like ship this thing
fast. And now we can say like, what's
the absolute best version of this
feature? Cuz
Claude's going to be the one building
it. So, what if you can build a team of
AI developers that work exactly the way
that you want them to? That's what
Brendan Dunn has figured out with his
custom sub agent system with Claude
Code. So, today on Builder Methods,
that's the new series on my channel
where my fellow builders are coming on
to share their screens and show exactly
how they work in this AI-first era.
Brendan joined me to pull back the
curtain on his entire workflow. Brendan
is a long-time builder, he's a SaaS
founder, and he runs Right Message,
which is a powerful personalization
platform. And what caught my attention
is how he uses a team of sub agents.
He's got a project management agent that
handles business requirements, a senior
developer agent that audits the codebase
and plans technical implementation, and
all of it connected to Linear for task
management. And so, in this video you'll
see how he sets all of that up and
defines those agent roles. You'll watch
how tasks flow through Linear as his AI
agents work. And he'll show us a demo of
a tool called Fern Desk that
automatically generates help
documentation by analyzing his code and
his Git commits. Now, if we haven't met,
I'm Brian Castle. I run Builder Methods
where I help professional builders stay
ahead of the curve when it comes to
building with AI. And every Friday I
send my Builder Briefing. That's a
5-minute read to help you stay sharp in
your craft. You can get yours by going
to buildermethods.com.
You'll find the notes from today's
episode linked below. And if you're a
Builder Methods Pro member, you can
access the full unedited recording where
Brendan and I talked for over an hour
about his complete system and his
journey in this industry starting from
in the pre-AI days when he was a
full-stack builder to how he has
transitioned to fully adopting AI to run
his SaaS business. All right, let's dive
in. I I only recently learned the term
uh CDP or customer data platform, but
we're kind of that in the sense that we
bridge together your email platform or
CRM with your site. So, basically when
somebody comes from your site, assuming
we can ID them and we have different
ways of doing that, uh we'll pull from
your the your email platform's API
everything you know about them. And then
we built like a um
a visual flowchart builder for saying,
okay, if they're anonymous, show the
pop-up that gets them on the list. And
if they're not anonymous, are they
tagged customer? And if they're not, you
know, show a little advert for a
product. But we also do Optimizely-style
like
go into our editor, click the heading,
um and say, when they're segmented this
way, change the heading to be ABC or
whatever it is. All right. So, Brendan's
about to show us how his sub agent
system actually works. He's got these
custom Claude.md files that define
different agent roles. And what's
interesting is how they chain together.
The project manager handles the business
side, then automatically hands off to
the senior developer for the technical
planning. Watch how it all flows. I ran
a prompt like right before I switched
over to talk to you, so we'll see what
it did and All right.
Um so, I I always like to start this
part off uh before we even get into the
code. Like, what's your setup in your
office there? Are you doing like one
monitor? What what like Uh I well, I've
got I've got one display. So, can you
see okay?
Yeah. Um
Yeah, that looks good.
>> So, I've got um So, you're you're a one
display guy like me. Everyone's doing
like two, three. No, I used to I have my
laptop over here, but that's honestly
only to play like YouTube videos.
That's okay. When I'm waiting for like
stuff to happen, I might like watch
something over here. But that's it. Like
I don't do anything email and
everything. Like I'm I'm very much like,
you know, it's all very much um
well, I'll open more stuff so you can
see.
So, like I've got, you know, here's my
email, here's help help scout and stuff
and I can just quickly like rapid-fire
go through stuff. So, I single display.
Um
>> way. I just I I had the second display
for for years and I I realized like I'm
not I'm not putting anything over there.
I'm I'm I'm focused here, you know?
Well, you know it's funny, I just
downgraded from a 32-in to a 27-in
display. Like I'm I realized like too
much neck turning. Like I want I don't
need I don't need anything big, you
know? So, This is a development in your
40s, you know? Yeah, well, exactly.
Yeah. So, I have a a mini LED 27-in
display, which I I love cuz it's like it
looks really nice.
It's not a 5K display, it's only 4K. Um
but it's I can't tell. And uh it was it
was cheap, so yeah. Good stuff.
>> I'm happy with it. But yeah, my my usual
setup is so, I daily drive Linux. Um
I Okay.
>> and and I use a window manager called
Nيري, which is really nice cuz I can
like, you know, like I said, like go
through stuff really fast and it's not
>> not doing like uh a Mochi or any any of
that?
>> No. No, I mean, I don't um
Yeah, I
I've seen it. Like it's it's cool, but
it's not for me.
Yeah, yeah. Where So, have you been
running Linux like for for a long time?
Uh
a while-ish. I used to run it in in high
school like back in the early 2000s.
Um
And then I switched to Mac like
everyone. And then I just haven't I
haven't like been happy with the
direction of macOS for a while. So, I
bailed. And
I do miss it at times. Like Mac MacBooks
are legitimately like the best machines
ever. Um
but you know, it's I'm running a
Framework laptop, which is kind of cool
cuz you can like upgrade bit piecemeal
and I can say I want to put a new hard
drive in or I want to upgrade the CPU or
whatever else. Nice.
>> Um but yeah, it's nice. Like you know,
I'm running um
what I think is a very minimal setup in
the sense that I I can I have dedicated
screens for everything. So, I have my
like support screen, which is email and
Help Scout. I can go to my coding
screen, which is what you see on the on
here. My first screen is what I had
Riverside on, which is my web browser
stuff.
And then the fourth one is usually like
WhatsApp and chat stuff. Um
So, yeah, that's pretty much all I need.
And then I just have like four main
workspaces, I guess. And Yeah. Sweet.
So, so you so you come in and like you
you basically like fire up those screens
uh every day and like what you know,
what are your daily drivers? Uh you've
got Claude Code in there. Yeah, so I I
run tmux uh in a terminal, which I have
um you know, I have Neovim, Claude Code,
the just our terminal stuff, and then my
web server. Um so, I have all these in
here.
Uh the AI tab is Claude Code over here.
And then um
this is the, you know,
the codebase. Um
I also can switch between various
projects. So, like one nice thing about
tmux is I can jump in and out of like
different little things like my config
and
for the system and stuff like that
really easily. Um but yeah, I mostly
live between these two tabs, which is
Neovim
and Claude Code. Uh
>> I haven't tried So, I I've been a big
Cursor user as like my daily as both my
IDE and and I run the terminal in in
there.
Um
and I I haven't looked at uh Go- you
know, Google's new anti-gravity thing,
but one of the one of the features I
want to like really check out there is
that you can actually run like multiple
workspaces in a single window. Whereas
like Cursor like I I throw like three
different cursors on different screens.
Ah, okay.
>> Yeah. Um
Yeah.
>> Yeah, I would um I mean, I've seen like
they have
uh
Claude Squad, I think, was one of them.
Like they have different Is that what
you're talking about? Like different
ways of
>> Yeah, like if I if I just need to like
hop into like three different codebases
or three different places on my on my
machine. Like I guess technically you
probably could do it in Cursor, but it's
kind of clunky and Yeah.
Yeah, I mean, what I like about the the
tmux setup I have here is I can actually
connect to it from my phone. So, I can
like shell into my machine
and like continue with a Claude Code
discussion. Do you ever do that?
>> What's that? Do you do that? Yeah.
>> Like in practice? Mhm. I do. Oh, wow.
>> Yeah. Cuz like that's something I you
know, I have started playing around with
like Claude Code on the web. You so you
can run the run the cloud agent and and
I've played around with that like have a
feature idea and like I'll I'll be
sitting on the couch and have it do do
it and I'll show up in the morning and
it's done. Um and I have not But but I I
feel like the thing that I would want to
do more is actually, you know, tunnel
into my actual machine and continue the
work that I was doing earlier in
>> all your like environmental variables
and you have all that other stuff, which
is like you can only do so much by like
just looking at the pure codebase. Since
it can't like hit the endpoint on your
dev server and like expec- like is it
coming back with a successful response?
Can you tell me may- like are there like
examples of workflows where that's
really useful for you? Like
How does that fit into your work day or
your life? Like so you maybe like you
start work in the earlier in the day,
then you go out, but you want to like
finish something from mobile. What what
does that look like? It's more like I
mean, the I most I don't
dictate
uh like I don't build new stuff mobile
if if that makes sense. But usually
it'll be let's say it's a long-running
task and I need to go like cook dinner,
right? I might um
just open up the phone after however
like it doesn't ping me when it's done.
I know there are ways of doing that, but
at the at the minute I just kind of like
open up the shell on my phone,
connect and see like did Claude spit out
all of its stuff showing that it's done
its its project. And then it's just more
of like I'll look at it and I'll
cuz sometimes it'll come back with like
a question that I'll block it, right? So
if that's the case I don't want to keep
it. I'm in this weird and maybe you felt
this too in this weird position
sometimes where I feel like the cause
this thing could be working 24/7, should
I be like
you know, tending to it like letting it
chug and do its thing. I'm I'm a Claude
yellow guy. I I've got an alias that
just, you know, Claude yellow.
>> yellow.
Yeah, I don't yeah, I don't let it
but I'm I'm talking about like
directional if it has a question about
like
Oh, yeah. Should I do I do a lot of
that, um, but it's always up front. So
like that's the stuff that I'm I'm I I
mean I think it's
it's super interesting to me now that
like I I'll spend hours sometimes days
in the shaping, the planning, the the
back and forth with Claude like like
dialing in what what the plan is or what
the spec is.
And then and then it'll take like 10
minutes to build the thing that we've
been planning for a whole day, you know.
Um
Yeah, so my my way of doing that, um, is
I I have a few agents in Claude that do
like the
basically I I instead of doing like PRDs
locally in the code base, I use linear.
So I use the linear MCP
and I will add like I will flush out the
tasks that way. So
I'll have like an agent that does
like reviews the code base and figures
out the best way to architect this new
feature and blah blah blah blah blah. It
dumps it in a linear task.
And then I have a another agent that
will then
um, whenever it starts working on a
linear task, it'll create a feature
branch locally, do its Can you take me
through that? So like how do you how do
you kick off so you're talking about
like a new feature?
Yeah, yeah. So, um Like how how would
you kick that off? What would be a like
your first step?
>> So let me just show you real quick.
Um, so
Okay, so I have
which one is it? I think it's agent
project manager, right? Um, and if I
were to use this, this instantiates
the context king which does like a
review of the existing code base, a
senior developer agent. Um, I don't
think it actually I've ever used this
pair developer thing.
A committer
that does nice commits and then a
browser tester which will use an MCP of
puppeteer to do like browser testing and
stuff.
Um, but then I basically just use
Go delete.
And those are sub agents that you have
in Claude code?
Or
>> Uh, yes.
>> Commands?
>> Yeah. Yeah. So I, um
There's the sub agents that invoke other
sub agents. So the main one I only ever
invoke is the project manager one
and that will then invoke the context
one to review and that's what populates
the the linear task. So my my thinking
is
um, and I could probably show you how I
do that.
Um, let me just find this.
So I have in here
So we're in Claude, we're in we're
inside agents, we're looking at Yeah, so
like this is what it does. This is how
it does stuff in linear, reads the task,
check the status,
when it's doing stuff update or launch
the agent linear updater to update the
task description as necessary
And you have like the linear MCP
connected.
>> Yeah, by the linear MCP. Um, so the idea
is I use linear to basically track and
the benefit of that is I could then use
like an exception tool to add stuff to
linear. So
it can put the whole dump of like the
the exception into a linear task and
then I can just tell Claude like, "Hey,
linear task 123 needs fixing or
something."
Um, so I can do it that way or I can
have it author linear tasks as new
features.
So this this agent here is the one that
is in charge of, um, like
you know, how it interacts with other
sub agents. So does like the, um,
you know, defines like its job is to
come up with the UI UX acceptance
criteria
which then goes to the browser testing
agent and all that stuff. So
I mean I didn't write any of this. I
used Claude to then write write that. I
was just going to ask you like how did
how did you put together your set of of
agents and your workflow?
agent stuff like I would anything else.
It's just my So so like but like you
from from ground zero like when you were
sort of just getting started with this
or whatever version you're on on this
like
you're like, "All right, I I need I need
to figure out a way to have an agent be
able to spin up a linear issue and write
it up in the way that I want it." So you
gave a prompt and and built a sub agent.
To do this thing.
>> told it instead of doing it through the
like create agent uh, thing that it you
can do in Claude, I instead just pointed
it to like, you know, the the hidden dot
Claude directory to the agent thing and
said, "Hey, create a project manager.md.
Here's what it needs in it. This is
going to be an agent that does X, Y, and
Z. Here are the other sub agents that
I'd like you to create that it will be
able to kind of invoke." So basically
the thinking the project manager is like
the the general contractor and then it
just fires off stuff to these different
sub agents that does stuff like
you know,
yeah, everything is Yeah, so so so under
that we we've got senior developer, pair
developer, browser tester, context king,
summarizer.
>> two to battle. So I have two agents.
This one does the first pass and then
this one fights back and says, "You
architected this dumb." So you just saw
how Brennan's agents work within Claude
code, but here's where it gets really
practical. He's integrated all of this
with linear, the popular issue tracking
tool, which is something that I use as
well. So as his agents work, they're
creating tasks, they're adding comments,
they're logging progress. So let's kick
it back to Brennan and let's see how a
completed feature looks in linear after
the AI builds it. So you've got your
your project manager, you want to start
up this new feature,
uh, you're you're calling on that
project manager sub agent through Claude
code. You're giving it I I guess you're
going to be giving it typically like a
raw description of what you want to do
just like off the top of your head or do
you do you do any other like Sometimes
if I'm feeling fancy I'll like create a
markdown file and say like read this.
This is
you know, that way it's a little less
like I can do proper like bullet lists
and stuff. Um But like off of that off
of like whatever you give it here
what what are you going to have it do
next?
>> So this is what this agent will do which
I had that markdown file that showed
what this agent does, but it'll
basically it will create a linear task,
um, once it has all the context and it
will set a description on that task and
a, um
title.
And then
what it then does is it has the
uh, like the senior developer what
whatever it's called like go and do an
audit of Would you be able to pull up
linear and and like show a feature that
was built? Yeah. This would be one,
right? So it it wrote all of this stuff,
right? Mhm.
And then
And so what you mean is like it
initially started with sort of just like
the business requirements, but then this
was expanded out with technical
requirements.
>> it started like this stuff, right? And
then it would yeah, then it would get
into the
tech which this would get it as an
update to the description, right? So it
would do the audit and say, "Okay, we
need like these view components created.
We need this back end service written.
This is what that back end service needs
to have."
blah blah blah blah. Yeah, so so it's
all just right here. Um
and this ends up being like
cuz one other thing I'm I'm using an app
called, um, Fern Desk for documentation.
So it'll actually read from linear and
get commits and write help docs based on
that. So
this has all the like the business
requirements
and then the commits obviously have the
technical like this is where it is in
the app. Um, Fern Desk will then
generate
like the help docs based on this stuff.
>> That's amazing. I've I've heard of that.
I haven't, uh, I feel like I need to to
get on that.
>> cool. Yeah, it's it's really nice. Um
But yeah, so that's pretty much the like
the flow is like I use this is I forgot
the name. There were I haven't seen it
talked about much, but there used to be
like a
terminal based like project management
tool like a PRD based thing.
Um
I don't know if you know the name of it,
but like I don't know what most people
are doing for Well, yeah, I mean like
the one I I was using for a while is it
was the one I created called agent OS.
Um
uh, but lately I've I've started to go a
lot more leaner than that, um
and just using like plan mode in both
Claude code or cursor. And you know,
like like
I only started I I also used to just say
like, "Don't even use plan mode. Just
just ask me questions."
Um, I started actually using plan mode
because it got really good, um, and then
now they now they've actually built in
like an interface for it to ask us
questions.
You know So I've seen that before and I
think the only time I the only reason I
haven't like it's not muscle memory to
use plan mode
is for a while it didn't work in yellow
mode.
Um, yeah. Yeah, I think it does now.
I've always been in yellow mode cuz I
hate being like, "Do you want to update
this file?" It's like, "Yes, update that
file." Yeah, yeah. I use Git for a
reason. Like you don't need your
permission. For sure.
So, um,
yeah. I like all right, so so you built
out the the linear issue, you've got the
business case, you've got the technical
plan there. Are you having it just roll
right into development or are you sort
of like putting it there and maybe
coming back another day to have it
built?
I mean, you know, Claude will tell me,
"Here's your like timeline view." Like
Yeah, it'll take 2 days.
>> This will take 3 weeks. No, this is
happening now.
I love how it still like gives time
estimates like like human time
estimates, yeah.
It's like, "No, no, Claude. Doing this
right now."
Uh no, I usually don't You can't You
can't clock in for the day, but Yeah,
exactly. Yeah. I mean, what I'll usually
do is part of the agent is to create a
feature branch locally. So, it'll do
that. It'll then write all the code.
I've I've got I've done things before
and I'm like, "Ah, this is stupid. Let's
just kill it." And then you just delete
the branch and
you know, wasted a bunch of time and
tokens doing stuff, but
>> This is I you know, I I get into these
like debates on Twitter and Blue Sky
with
developer friends who are who are kind
of slow to
to adopt AI. And one of the things is
like I I've been saying just yesterday
was like
it allows us to be more ambitious with
our products and our features. I mean,
just a year or two 3 years ago
a
the idea of like building a whole
feature and then just throwing it out
would be like, "That was such a waste of
time and money and resources."
Or building a whole feature and be and
maybe getting 80% in and realizing, "Ah,
there's something fundamentally wrong
about how we went about this."
Let's just Let's just patch it up and
ship it because we have to ship this
thing. Now we can just start over, you
know? And it's not a big deal. And it
it's just like that I think that's where
we start to see the improvement in
actual
quality is like
we we could build it multiple times to
to truly get it right, you know? Or the
I mean, the other thing is like we could
it it The mindset used to be like
"What is the just good enough version of
this feature?" Because we're
bootstrappers and we want to like ship
this thing fast. And now we can say
like, "What's the absolute best version
of this feature?" Cuz
Claude's going to be the one building
it, so Exactly. Yeah, I mean, I I think
you're right in that like you're able to
kind of
test a new idea really quickly
and
my concern is that I worry about this
with myself is that
you always want a very lean and
opinionated product. And it's too easy
nowadays to build. So, it's like
it's easier for me I think to add scope
creep and and feature creep, but I can
I think honestly I'm
the way I look at it is you know, we've
got a we've got a good product, but
we're not like massive. We have 250
paying customers. So,
I can like ship something kind of today
explain it to people, get them to try to
use it.
And if everyone says it like sucks, I've
no issue with being like, "Well, let's
let's either do it right or like kill
it." Um so
yeah, I I think I'm like I would have
never done that in the old ways of like
where it's we take months to like plan
and build this stuff, but
yeah. I think like the the hard thing
about products is still hard. Like like
making a great product that actually
works for customers and sustains over
time, like that's that's always going to
be hard. And that and that's that's
always going to require us to
to to make, you know, smart business
decisions, right? Um
But now this next part is something I
hadn't seen before. Brendan's using a
tool called Fern Desk that connects to
his codebase and to Linear, and it
writes help documentation automatically.
So, it reads his code, it looks at his
Git commits, and his Linear tasks, and
then generates actual help articles.
Check it out. Like how does Fern Desk
work? What's what's what's something
that it wrote up?
>> so how it works is
Um so
first thing it is always looking at like
So, this is a bad example one, but like
um
it'll look at like what people are
asking about and um
Again, problem is we've been doing
webinars and people write into support
with like stuff about that.
Um Is the webinar going to be recorded?
Well, I'll show you like this. Like um
So, here's here's a prompt that I put
in. So, I said like
"In this I've a contacts and people help
helped us section, create a new article
explaining how our new people feature
works, which you'll find the most recent
commits to in the codebase. This feature
helps you get a live view of who's on
your website or WriteMessage offers
forms blah blah blah." So, it did that.
It looked through the codebase and then
it drafted this and it tells you about
like these are the various things and
like here's what you like these are the
different tabs and what they show and
stuff.
Um so, it's super nice in the sense that
I can like this is what I like
Uh where's one um
Like here's another one
where I'm like
"Write a help doc in website
personalization section that documents
how the data RMF logic works." And then
I just give it files like and tag the JS
for manually doing this.
Let people know that they can find blah
blah blah blah blah. Make it clear. And
it just writes like
It does the
>> it's like it's getting the underlying
functionality by actually analyzing your
codebase. Yeah. Yeah.
That's cool. So, it's really that's
awesome. And then it also So, um
pulls out of like if you look at what
it's integrated with, it's integrated
with Help Scout, GitHub, Linear.
I don't know why it's with my Gmail,
too. But like it it integrates with a
like a lot of the tools I think we all
use.
>> That's awesome. Um and then it can just
do like audits and
like
even this like
"Update the JavaScript hooks article to
include our new identify by email opt
option that I added." So, I added a new
thing in the codebase and it looked at
the code and then it just figured out
what to add to it, which is the this
thing.
And it, you know, details how to use it,
all that stuff. So,
I'm really bullish on this. Like I think
this is really cool. Um Yeah, I mean,
like I I could see like in in
WriteMessage you are like actively
obviously running the business and and
actively talking to customers.
I've I've some products that I'm
actually trying to like
have them sort of run on autopilot while
I focus on a new product. Mhm. And uh
I I I have started like with like AI in
our customer support. It's it's been
interesting cuz I give the I give
customers an option to talk to the
chatbot or talk to a human. Okay.
>> It's it's actually interesting to see
how like quite often they actually
choose the chatbot to try to get a quick
answer.
All right. Okay. And um
I've I've been sort of impressed with
the answers. Sometimes it gets things
wrong, which but that's where like
better documentation would make our
whole system
>> Cuz the chatbot would train on your
docs, Yeah, exactly. Yeah. Yeah,
what I'm looking I mean, eventually I
would like to have like a tier one AI
agent thing that people can at least
talk to.
Yeah. And my expectation there is that
this this the docs that is that are
being created, which you can see them
all like
you know, here, right? Like It would
just
>> interesting cuz like they are treating
it like a search. Like
>> Yeah. Uh Exactly. Yeah. Cuz we have a
like you can go to our help our our help
docs page and use our search. Mhm. But
they want they're they're in the app, so
they want to use the widget. Right.
>> And then I can see the the transcript of
the AI chat with customers and they're
they're not asking questions. They're
just putting search queries in there.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah.
>> really cool feature. Tell me something.
>> this tool is going to do that eventually
cuz it actually shows you like
you know, whether it's like what people
are typing in. Is it a miss? Is it a
hit? Um a lot of people looking for
beehive, which we don't integrate with.
Um GDPR is a miss. Yeah. So, like
I had imagined with the AI bot it would
be basically the same thing. And I think
they're actually working on like
this being AI enabled at some point.
They'll have like a widget that just you
know
searches it.
>> That's what it is. Yeah, that's that's
what we have. You know, what stands out
about Brendan's approach is how
systematic he is about the whole thing.
He's not just prompting Claude and
hoping for the best. He's built an
entire infrastructure around it. The
sub-agent pattern for keeping context
focused, the Linear integration for
persisting the AI's thinking, and that
Fern Desk setup for documentation that
updates itself. Now, if you want to see
more of how Brendan thinks through these
problems, you can access our full
unedited conversation where for over an
hour we go deep on his complete toolkit
and his journey in this industry. You
can get that by becoming a Builder
Methods Pro member by going to
buildermethods.com/pro.
You'll get access to all the interviews
and all the workshops, plus you can join
our community of builders and get my
full library of courses on building with
AI. And if you want to learn more about
setting up Claude Code for yourself like
we saw in Brendan's workflow, don't miss
my video covering my favorite new
features that dropped in Claude Code
recently. So, right after you hit
subscribe on the channel, I'll see you
over there next. Let's keep building.